Guide to the Paul Horgan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Paul Horgan papers
1949-2014
YCAL MSS 845
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
104.18
225 boxes + 1 art, 1 roll, 9 record album storage.
The papers contain correspondence, writings, printed material, photographs, artwork, sound recordings, video recordings, and financial papers.
Horgan, Paul, 1903-1995
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 220-230 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 231-234: Restricted until 2040. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Scope and Contents
The papers contain correspondence, writings, printed material, photographs, artwork, sound recordings, video recordings, and financial papers.
Biographical / Historical
Paul Horgan, American author of fiction and non-fiction. Horgan was born in Buffalo, New York, in 1903, and moved to Albuquerque, New Mexico in 1915. He attended the New Mexico Military Institute in Roswell and later worked as the institute's librarian. Horgan enrolled in the Eastman School of Music in Rochester, New York in 1923. Horgan first came to prominence when he won the Harper Prize in 1933 for The Fault of Angels, drawn instead from his experiences in Rochester. Horgan had a long academic relationship with Wesleyan University in Middletown, Connecticut. The author Charles Barber served as a personal assistant to Horgan while Barber was in college. Horgan died in 1995. He published forty books and received nineteen honorary degrees from universities in the United States.
Custodial History
Gift of Paul Horgan, 1955-2004. Purchased from Paul Horgan on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1987. Gift of Joseph W. and Kit Reed, 2006-2013.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials; Autobiographies (documents); Drawings (visual works); Photographs; Photograph albums; Scrapbooks; Slides (photographs); Sound recordings; Video recordings; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Horgan, Paul, 1903-1995
- Early Acquisitions, 1922-1980; 49.32; (124 Boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Former call number: ZA Horgan
  - Writings
    - The Garden Rose, printed, undated (Box 1)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      Gift of Carl Van Vechten, March 1954
    - Great River, vol. 1, undated; 5 (Box 1)
    - Great River, vol. 2, undated; 5 (Box 2)
    - Great River, setting typescript, undated; 5 (Box 3)
    - Great River, setting typescript, undated; 5 (Box 4)
    - Great River, galley proof, 2 (Box 5)
    - The Centuries of Santa Fe, original typescript, undated (Box 6)
    - The Centuries of Santa Fe, galley proof, 1956 (Box 6)
    - The Centuries of Santa Fe, English edition copy, part one, undated (Box 7)
    - The Saintmaker's Christmas Eve, undated (Box 7)
    - One Red Rose, a dramatization of the novel by Paul Horgan, undated (Box 7)
    - Body of Work, 1957 (Box 7)
    - Give Me Possession, typescript, undated (Box 7)
    - Give Me Possession, setting typescript, undated; 2 (Box 8)
    - Give Me Possession, galley proofs, undated (Box 8)
    - Mountain Standard Time: introduction, afterword, and Far From Cibola, undated (Box 8)
    - Mountain Standard Time: Main Line West, Far from Cibola, The Common Heart, galley proofs and setting copy, undated; 3 (Box 9)
    - A Distant Trumpet, original typescript, undated; 5 (Box 10)
    - A Distant Trumpet, original typescript, undated (Box 11)
    - Conquistadors in North American History, original typescript, undated (Box 11)
    - Conquistadors in North American History, galley proofs, undated (Box 11)
    - Things As They Are, original setting typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - Pages From a Rio Grande Notebook, original typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - To The Castle, typescript, undated; 2 (Box 12)
    - Muzza, typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - The Magic in the Mask, typescript, undated; 2 (Box 12)
    - Original Sin, typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - Black Snowflakes, typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - Toby and the Nighttime, typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - Trial By Fire, typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - A Passion for Useless Information, typescript, undated; 2 (Box 12)
    - The Treasure by the Brook, typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - From the Royal City, typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - Everything to Live For
      - Original typescript draft, undated (Box 13)
      - Revised first draft, undated (Box 13)
      - Notes for revision, undated (Box 13)
      - Setting typescript, undated (Box 13)
      - Galley proofs, undated (Box 14)
      - Page proof, undated (Box 14)
      - Plate proof, undated (Box 14)
    - A Distant Trumpet, setting typescript, undated; 4 (Box 15)
    - A Distant Trumpet, setting typescript, undated (Box 16)
    - Conquistadors in North American History: Mexico notes, notebook, undate (Box 16)
    - Great River: Prologue, "Riverscape," original typed draft, undated (Box 16)
    - Hurd, Peter, "South Plains Mural" dedication speech, undated (Box 16)
    - Rain in Laredo, first draft typescript, undated (Box 16)
    - Memories of the Future, setting typescript, undated (Box 16)
    - Memories of the Future, galley proofs, undated (Box 17)
    - The Peach Stone, galley proofs, undated (Box 17)
    - Things As They Are
      - Notes, undated (Box 18)
      - Original Sin, undated (Box 18)
      - The Dawn of Hate, undated (Box 18)
      - Muzza, undated (Box 18)
      - Far Kingdoms, undated (Box 18)
      - Magic, notes, undated (Box 18)
      - Black Snowflakes, undated (Box 18)
      - Center of Interest, undated (Box 18)
      - The Spoiled Priest, undated (Box 18)
      - A Discharge of Electricity, undated (Box 18)
      - Parma Violets, undated (Box 18)
      - Galley proofs, undated (Box 18)
    - The Thin Mountain Air
      - Galley proofs, undated (Box 19)
      - Setting typescript, undated; 3 (Box 19)
      - Revised page proof, 1977 March 22 (Box 20)
      - Page proof, 1977 April 28 (Box 20)
      - Uncorrected page proof, bound, 1977 (Box 21)
      - Repro proofs, 1977 June 8 (Box 21)
      - Plate proofs, 1977 (Box 22 (Oversize))
    - Approaches to Writing
      - Setting typescript, undated (Box 21)
      - Proofs, undated (Box 21)
      - Bibliography, undated (Box 23)
      - Revised proof, undated (Box 23)
      - Master proofs, undated; 2 (Box 23)
  - Manuscripts
    - Boynton, Peter, memorial to, undated (Box 24)
    - Bugles in the Sunrise, undated (Box 24)
    - Bynner, Witter: Selected Poems: preface, undated (Box 24)
    - Bynner, Witter: letters concerning literary estate, 1970 July 13 (Box 24)
    - The Calm of Order, undated (Box 24)
    - Caricatures, clipping, undated (Box 24)
    - Carter, Alfred: Thirty Poems, undated (Box 24)
    - Citizen of New Salem, clippings, undated (Box 24)
    - The Common Heart, undated (Box 24)
    - Conquistadors in North America, undated (Box 24)
    - The Devil in the Desert, undated (Box 24)
    - The Devil's Trill, undated (Box 24)
    - A Distant Harbor, undated; 2 (Box 24)
    - A Distant Trumpet, undated; 2 (Box 24)
    - A Distant Trumpet, correspondence, 1960-1966 (Box 24)
    - A Distant Trumpet, photographs, undated (Box 24)
    - A Distant Trumpet, screenplay, undated (Box 24)
    - Dempster MacMurphy obituary, undated (Box 25)
    - Sister Beatrice by Maeterlinck and translated by Paul Horgan, 1926 (Box 25)
    - Memories of the Future, undated (Box 25)
    - American Pictures, undated (Box 25)
    - Americanism, undated (Box 25)
    - Bedside Manner, undated (Box 25)
    - Buffalo Scenes, undated (Box 25)
    - Burning Pine, undated (Box 25)
    - The Change, undated (Box 25)
    - Children's Books and the Popular Arts, undated (Box 25)
    - The Church Wedding, undated (Box 25)
    - A Duty Call, undated (Box 25)
    - The End of the Dream, undated (Box 25)
    - Footnote to a Timetable, undated (Box 25)
    - For a Life, undated (Box 25)
    - The Great Canary Diamond, undated (Box 25)
    - A Literary News Reel, undated (Box 25)
    - A Little Undertow, undated (Box 25)
    - The Meaning of a Museum, undated (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 25)
    - Muses of the Frontier, undated (Box 25)
    - Point of Honor, undated (Box 25)
    - The Rope, undated (Box 25)
    - Summer Stock, undated (Box 25)
    - Super and Superwoman, undated (Box 25)
    - A Suppressed Episode, undated (Box 25)
    - The Time I Couldn't See Mrs. Fiske, undated (Box 25)
    - Two Conductors, undated (Box 25)
    - The Valedictory, undated (Box 25)
    - War Sketches, 1941-1943 (Box 25)
    - Words to Live By, undated (Box 25)
    - Worlds and Tempests, undated (Box 25)
  - Notes
    - Drawings, undated (Box 26)
    - Encounters with Stravinsky, letter, 1972 September 13 (Box 26)
    - Encounters with Stravinsky, notes, undated (Box 26)
    - Santa Fe, 1962-1963; 2 (Box 26)
    - Travel, undated (Box 26)
    - [Str. cond.?] and rehearsing, undated (Box 26)
    - Work, undated (Box 26)
    - [Rest of Realizations?] part II, undated (Box 26)
    - To the Last- Part III, undated (Box 26)
    - V. Stravinsky and R. Croft, correspondence, undated (Box 26)
    - Discussion/ I.S.-N.C. books, undated (Box 26)
    - Santa Fe, 1957-1961; 5 (Box 27)
    - London, 1959 (Box 27)
    - Houston, 1958 (Box 27)
    - Appendices and index, undated (Box 27)
    - Clippings and correspondence, undated (Box 27)
    - Encounters with Stravinsky, revision of part I, undated (Box 27)
  - Printed material
    - Awakenings, 1973 (Box 28)
    - South Dakota Review: volume 11, number 3, 1973 (Box 28)
    - The Range of Literature: Fiction, 1973 (Box 28)
    - The Form of Marriage in Spanish North America by Hans W. Baade, 1976 (Box 28)
    - The Cowboy Reader edited by Lon Tinkle and Allen Maxwell, 1959 (Box 28)
    - Catalog of the Western Research Collection of the Pueblo Regional Library District, 1976 August (Box 28)
    - The Saturday Evening Post, 1962 January 27 (Box 28)
  - Writings
    - Encounters with Stravinksy
      - First draft, undated; 3 (Box 29)
      - Setting typescript, undated; 3 (Box 29)
      - Galley proofs, undated; 2 (Box 30)
      - Page proof (Box 31)
    - Everything to Live For, undated (Box 31)
    - The Fault of Angels, undated (Box 31)
    - The Fault of Angels (play), notes, undated (Box 31)
    - The Fault of Angels (play), manuscript, undated (Box 31)
    - Fergusson, Erna and New Mexico: an Introduction, undated (Box 31)
    - Figures in a Landscape, undated (Box 31)
    - Georgetown University, 1962 March 22 (Box 32)
    - Goddard, Robert Hutchings: Statement in honor of, undated (Box 32)
    - Great River, undated; 2 (Box 32)
    - Great River (symphonic poem), undated (Box 32)
    - The Habit of Empire, photographs, undated (Box 32)
    - The Heroic Triad, undated; 4 (Box 32)
    - The Heroic Triad, galley proofs, undated (Box 33)
    - The Heroic Triad, letters and reviews, undated (Box 33)
    - Humanities, National Endowment for the, 1966, undated; 4 (Box 33)
    - Hunter, R. Vernon, undated (Box 33)
    - Hurd, Peter, 1939 (Box 33)
    - Hurd, Peter: A Portrait Sketch from Life, 1964 (Box 33)
    - Kennedy, J. F., television script, undated (Box 33)
    - Lincoln Play, first draft, undated (Box 34)
    - Lincoln Play, second draft, undated (Box 34)
    - Lincoln Play, old draft, undated; 3 (Box 34)
    - Loyola College, 1968 (Box 34)
    - More to Believe In, notes, undated (Box 35)
    - More to Believe In, undated (Box 35)
    - Ney, Elisabet, undated (Box 35)
    - No Quarter Given, undated (Box 35)
    - Notes for Poetry in America, 1925 (Box 35)
    - Notes on Writing Fiction, undated (Box 35)
    - One Red Rose for Christmas, script, 1967 (Box 35)
    - The Passing Bell, undated (Box 35)
    - The Peach Stone, story, undated (Box 35)
    - The Peach Stone, letters, 1967 (Box 35)
    - Period Piece, undated (Box 35)
    - Shrady, Frederick, The Sculpture of, undated (Box 36)
    - The Silver Lamp, undated (Box 36)
    - Slonimsky, Nicholos, songbook inscribed by, 1957 (Box 36)
    - The Small Rain, notes, 1954-1966 (Box 36)
    - The Small Rain, undated (Box 36)
    - Snow, C. P: The Malcontents, book review, undated (Box 36)
    - Songs After Lincoln, 1964 (Box 36)
    - Songs After Lincoln, letters and reviews, 1966-1967 (Box 36)
    - A Speaking Likeness, undated (Box 36)
    - A Start in Life, notes, undated (Box 36)
    - A Start in Life, undated (Box 36)
    - The Surgeon and the Nun, undated (Box 36)
    - Texans, First Epistle vs. the, undated (Box 36)
    - Things As They Are, undated; 2 (Box 36)
    - Thomason, John, undated (Box 36)
    - To Every Goliath, manuscripts, undated (Box 37)
    - To Every Goliath, 1938; 2 (Box 37)
    - To the Mountains, letters, undated (Box 37)
    - A Tree on the Plains, outline, undated (Box 37)
    - A Tree on the Plains, undated (Box 37)
    - U.S. Defense Department, 1951 (Box 37)
    - Rachel, undated (Box 38)
    - Relatives Out West, notes, undated (Box 38)
    - A Roman Death, undated (Box 38)
    - Rome Eternal, photographs, undated (Box 38)
    - Royal Recollections, galley proofs, undated (Box 38)
    - The Saintmaker's Christmas Eve, television script, undated (Box 38)
    - A Shadow in Spring, undated (Box 38)
    - We Never End, undated; 3 (Box 39)
    - White House, memoranda, undated (Box 39)
    - Whitewater, notes, undated (Box 39)
    - Whitewater, letters and clippings, undated (Box 39)
    - The Vigil, undated; 2 (Box 39)
    - The Virtuoso, undated (Box 39)
    - Writings of Margaret Fuller
      - Hear the Reverend, undated (Box 40)
      - Her Son, galley proof, 1929 (Box 40)
      - Her Son, typescript, undated (Box 40)
      - His Little Britisher, 1936 (Box 40)
    - Drawing by Paul Horgan, signed, undated (Box 41)
    - Watercolor by Paul Horgan, original, undated (Box 41)
    - Lamy of Santa Fe
      - Notebooks A-C, 1968, undated (Box 41)
      - Notebooks 2-3, 1967, undated (Box 41)
      - Notebooks 5, 6, undated (Box 41)
      - Notebooks, 1973 (Box 41)
      - Notebooks, undated (Box 42)
      - Miscellaneous Lamy Material received November 1976
        - Baltimore Archives, undated (Box 42)
        - Weekly New Mexican, undated (Box 42)
        - Texas Catholic Archives, undated (Box 42)
        - VPF 1852-1885, undated (Box 42)
        - Santa Fe New Mexican Review, undated (Box 42)
        - ALS, undated (Box 42)
        - RA, undated (Box 42)
        - Reconnoissances' of Routes from San Antonio De Dexar and unidentified map, undated (Box 42)
        - Clippings and draft, undated (Box 42)
        - Scheme and outline, undated (Box 42)
        - Lectures and writings, undated (Box 42)
        - Lamy in Passage, undated (Box 42)
        - Draft, undated (Box 42)
        - Clippings and photocopies, undated (Box 42)
        - Correspondence and notes, undated (Box 42)
        - Notes, undated; 10 (Box 43)
        - Notes, undated; 10 (Box 44)
        - Notes, undated; 9 (Box 45)
        - Notes, undated; 5 (Box 46)
      - Bibliography for Lamy of Santa Fe (Box 47 (Oversize))
      - Stamps from archives visited, undated; 14 (Box 48 (Oversize))
    - Stravinsky Material
      Received April 1976
      - Robert Craft in Stravinsky's library, photograph, 1963 (Box 49)
      - Picasso drawing of Stravinsky, clipping, 1920 (Box 49)
      - Sir Eugene Goossens by Paul Horgan, caricature, 1924 (Box 49)
      - Stravinsky and Paul Horgan at a rehearsal of Oedipus Rex at the Santa Fe Opera, photograph, undated (Box 49)
      - Cathedral rehearsal Santa Fe, photograph, undated (Box 49)
      - Lamy- waiting for super chief, photographs, undated (Box 49)
      - Santa Fe cathedral, photograph, undated (Box 49)
      - Setting out for a drive in Central Park, photograph, undated (Box 49)
      - Hollywood, photograph, 1957 (Box 49)
      - Deleted photographs, undated (Box 49)
      - Firebird, illustration by Paul Horgan, 1924 (Box 49)
      - Bedell patio, Vera Stravinsky exhibition, photographs, 1962 (Box 49)
      - Stravinsky rehearsing in the cathedral at Santa Fe, undated (Box 49)
      - Encounters with Stravinsky: A Personal Record by Paul Horgan, 1972; 2 (Box 49)
      - Materials relating to New York City Ballet, 1971-1972 (Box 49)
      - Thank you note from Stravinsky, framed, 1966 March (Box 49)
      - Clippings and drafts relating to Encounters with Stravinsky, undated; 2 (Box 49)
      - New York City Ballet Stravinsky Festival, 1972 June (Box 49)
      - Saturday Review, 1971 May 29 (Box 49)
      - Materials relating to Igor Stravinsky bronze plaque, 1971 (Box 49)
      - Bakst, portrait of Vera de Bosset, 1922 (Box 49)
    - Great River, notecards, undated; 4 (Box 50)
    - Photographs of Robert Hunt by Carl Van Vechten, undated (Box 51)
    - Manuscripts
      - The Affair of the Yznaga Crown Jewels, typescript, 1979; 4 (Box 52)
      - All the Young Americans, film script, undated (Box 52)
      - American Autumn 1886, typescript, undated (Box 52)
      - Approaches to Writing
        - Typescript, undated (Box 52)
        - Xerox of setting copy, undated; 2 (Box 52)
        - Notes, undated (Box 53)
        - Page proof, undated (Box 53)
        - Two drafts, xerox copies, undated (Box 53)
        - Galley proofs, undated (Box 53)
        - Aspen Award Dinner Remarks, undated (Box 53)
      - Babin, Victor, Variations on a Theme by Beethoven, a note on, undated (Box 54)
      - Ballade, undated (Box 54)
        - The Devil's Trill, working notes, undated (Box 56)
      - A Brush with the Law, undated (Box 54)
      - Burning Pine, undated (Box 54)
      - By Lamplight, undated (Box 54)
      - The Catholic Hour: Rome Eternal, shows 1-4, stencil copies, undated (Box 54)
      - The Centuries of Santa Fe, illustrations, undated; 2 (Box 54)
      - The Common Heart, original draft, undated; 3 (Box 54)
      - The Common Heart, original draft, undated (Box 55)
      - The Common Heart, notes and rejections, undated (Box 55)
      - Corpus Christi, drawings, 1949 (Box 55)
      - Death in the Lenses, unpublished, undated (Box 55)
      - Death, Mr. President, carbon typescript, undated; 3 (Box 55)
      - Dear to the Muse, a play in three acts, undated (Box 55)
      - A Distant Trumpet, working notes, undated; 2 (Box 56)
      - A Distant Trumpet, king features proof sheet, undated (Box 56)
      - Dry River, unpublished carbon typescript, undated (Box 56)
      - Encounters with Stravinsky, notes, undated (Box 56)
      - Encounters with Stravinsky: A Personal Record, xerox typescript, undated (Box 56)
      - Encounters with Stravinsky: A Personal Record, xerox typescript, undated (Box 57)
      - The End of One, Two, Three, undated (Box 57)
      - Escape From the Present Tense, undated (Box 57)
      - Far From Cibola, undated (Box 57)
      - Father D'Arcy and the Ages of Man, undated (Box 57)
      - The Fault of Angels, carbon typescript (play), undated; 2 (Box 57)
      - Fidelity, typescripts, undated; 4 (Box 57)
      - The Food of Love, typescript, undated (Box 57)
      - Fort Delivery, stencil copy of typescript, undated (Box 57)
      - From the Battle of Hollywood, undated (Box 58)
      - From the Royal City, 1982 (Box 58)
      - Give Me Possession, carbon typescript, undated; 2 (Box 58)
      - The Golden Age of the American Theatre, undated (Box 58)
      - Graphics by Paul Horgan, undated (Box 58)
      - Great River, field notebooks, undated; 4 (Box 59)
      - Great River, typescript, undated (Box 59)
      - Great River, plates, undated (Box 59)
      - Green, Samuel, On the Paintings of, undated (Box 59)
      - The Harmony of Things Unlike, 1964 (Box 59)
      - Heroic Triad, galley proofs, undated; 2 (Box 60)
      - Heroic Triad, setting copy (xerox), undated (Box 60)
      - Houston, George, A Word for, undated (Box 61)
      - [Hurd, Peter] A Great New American Mural Painting, undated (Box 61)
      - Hurd, Peter: A Portrait Sketch From Life, typescript, undated (Box 61)
      - Johnson, Burges, Introduction, Roswell, New Mexico, undated (Box 61)
      - Journey to the Past- And Return: Reflections on the Work of the Historian, xerox of typescript, undated (Box 61)
      - Justice: A Short Historical Novel, original typescript and first carbon, undated; 2 (Box 61)
      - Lamy of Santa Fe
        - Lamy: Moments From the Life of the First Bishop and Archbishop of Santa Fe, carbon typescript, undated (Box 61)
        - Lamy and the Gateway, xerox of typescript, 1968 (Box 61)
        - Field sketch, undated (Box 61)
        - Notebook, undated (Box 61)
        - Notes, undated (Box 61)
        - Notes and miscellaneous manuscript material, undated; 2 (Box 61)
        - Index, typescript, undated (Box 62)
        - Notes, undated (Box 62)
        - Reference matter, undated (Box 62)
        - Setting typescript, undated; 2 (Box 62)
        - Original draft, typescript, undated; 4 (Box 63)
        - Notes, undated (Box 64)
        - Index and notes, proof, undated (Box 64)
        - Miscellaneous reference material, undated; 2 (Box 64)
        - Page proof, marked set, undated (Box 64)
        - Unbound sheets, 1975; 2 (Box 65)
        - Author's corrected galleys, 1975 (Box 66)
        - Page proofs, undated (Box 66)
        - Unbound sheets, first trade edition, 1975 (Box 66)
      - The Last Album, undated (Box 67)
      - John Caradine, photographs as Lincoln, undated (Box 67)
      - Little Benny, typescript, undated (Box 67)
      - Little Enough Pleasure, undated (Box 67)
      - The Last Escape of Billy the Kid, undated (Box 67)
      - London letter, 1970 (Box 67)
      - Lost River, undated; 2 (Box 67)
      - Lost River, carbon typescript, undated (Box 67)
      - Maeterlinck, Maurice. Sister Beatrice, translated by Paul Horgan, 1926 (Box 67)
      - Main Line West, 1935 (Box 67)
      - Man and Means, 1968 (Box 68)
      - The Man Called K (formerly A Passion for Useless Information), carbon typescript, undated; 3 (Box 68)
      - Martyrdom in Washington, carbon typescript, 1961; 3 (Box 68)
      - Maurice Baring Restored, notes, undated; 5 (Box 69)
      - Good Things, notes, undated (Box 69)
      - First Drafts of "Commentaries" by Paul Horgan in Maurice Baring Restored, undated (Box 70)
      - Draft and published lecture: Maurice Baring Reconsidered, 1969 (Box 70)
      - Introduction to Maurice Baring Restored, undated (Box 70)
      - Maurice Baring Restored, setting copy for text I-VII, undated; 3 (Box 71)
      - Maurice Baring Restored, setting copy for text VII-XI, undated (Box 72)
      - Memories of the Future, carbon typescript, 1946 (Box 73)
      - Memories of the Future, original typescript, 1946 (Box 73)
      - Memories of the Future, carbon typescript, undated (Box 73)
      - More to Believe In, 1939 (Box 73)
      - National Honeymoon, typescript, undated (Box 74)
      - No Quarter Given: Some People, 1935 (Box 74)
      - A Note on a Green Pair of Sunglasses, original typescript, undated (Box 74)
      - Novel, notes, undated; 2 (Box 74)
      - Novel, Raw Material of a, undated (Box 74)
      - Novels, The Making and Meaning of, undated (Box 74)
      - Old Army, undated (Box 74)
      - One Red Rose for Christmas, typescript, undated (Box 74)
      - One Red Rose for Christmas, TV adaptation by Leonard Moran, 1958 (Box 74)
      - Ordeal at Fort Reprisal, galley proof, undated (Box 74)
      - Out of the Rubble, typescript, undated (Box 74)
      - The Paris Feeling, carbon typescripts, undated; 2 (Box 74)
      - The Paris Feeling, stencil copy, 1951 (Box 74)
      - Parma Violets, carbon typescript, undated (Box 75)
      - Period Piece, undated (Box 75)
      - The Prairie Travellers, typescript, undate (Box 75)
      - Rachel, undated; 6 (Box 75)
      - Rain in Laredo, carbon typescript, undated (Box 76)